californiacolleges.edu 2016-01-18

# California Colleges - Privacy Policy

CaliforniaColleges.edu gives students guidance and support to plan and prepare for college and careers. XAP Corporation (XAP) is the website manager of CaliforniaColleges.edu. Using this website, you can create a student profile with your academic and school transcript information to help you with your educational goals.

This Privacy Policy explains how the CaliforniaColleges.edu website works and how XAP will work to keep your information safe and secure. As a student user, you have control over your data. Your personal information will not be shared outside of the CaliforniaColleges.edu website without your permission.

In addition to personal information that you provide to the website, your account may include information provided by your school district derived from your student records. That will be the case for districts or schools that automatically generate user accounts on your behalf, or that enter agreements with the CCGI to obtain services from CCGI to the district. For such districts, agreements between CCGI and the district limit the purposes for which and recipients to which personally identifiable information relating to you may be disclosed, whether the information is provided directly by you or by the school district. The information may be provided only to officials or employees of the district who have a legitimate interest in the information to help you prepare for college; to contractors of the district and their employees who have a parallel interest in the information; to colleges to which you have applied for admission; and to appropriate financial aid organizations in connection with certain determinations concerning your eligibility and conditions for an award of financial aid. If there is no agreement with the district that you attend for the district to provide information from your student records, the only information included in your account will be information that you provide, and you may designate the organizations or categories of officials who may receive that information.

You should review this Policy with your parent, a family member, or your school guidance counselor and talk with them about setting up a CaliforniaColleges.edu student account.

### Creating a Student Account

When you create a student account on CaliforniaColleges.edu, you are asked to “Find” the middle school, high school, postsecondary institution, or workforce center that you attend. At any time you can remove the connection between your portfolio and the school you attend, thereby disabling counselors at that school from accessing data in your account. You can do this by going to www.CaliforniaColleges.edu / Your Portfolio / Your Profile / The Basics / My Account is Connected to, and click on “Change.” Then find and click on “None Selected;” click “Continue.”

By selecting a school during this step, you are granting permission for authorized professionals at that school to view information that you enter into your CaliforniaColleges.edu portfolio, some of which may be personal information. If you do not wish to grant this permission, you may specify “None Selected” when asked to “Find” your school during account creation. Before allowing a school employee to view your information, we will work with your school district to confirm that the individual works at the school you attend and that the person has a legitimate interest in your data before that person will be able to view your information.

In the event that CaliforniaColleges.edu wishes to inform you about educational or financial aid and scholarship opportunities, it will only do so if, during your use of the Website, you checked "yes" to the opt-in question to receive such information.

### Reasons We Collect Your Personally Identifiable Information

When you are signed on to CaliforniaColleges.edu, your personally identifiable information is collected and stored for three primary reasons:

  1. We collect your information to help you perform specific tasks on CaliforniaColleges.edu such as completing a college admission application for the colleges that you specify. This includes our collection of information so that you can complete applications and other functions, such as scholarship searches and the Financial Aid Award Estimator, without having to re-type the same information repeatedly. (See the next section of this Policy for other tasks.)
  2. We collect your information to allow the employees at your school or a community-based organization whom you specifically approve (like your school counselor or teacher, or after-school mentor), to view information you store in your career and college planning portfolio. This allows these individuals to work with you on activities you accomplish on the CaliforniaColleges.edu website.
  3. We collect your information so that we can respond to your questions or contact you when necessary in connection with the functioning of the CaliforniaColleges.edu website.

When a CaliforniaColleges.edu module does not require personal information to function effectively, no personal information is collected. Many parts of our website are available and can be accessed without creating or logging on to an account or providing any personal data.

### Ways In Which Personally Identifiable Information May Be Used

CaliforniaColleges.edu can help you in your college and career planning. When you direct us to, we will use your personal information to help you complete certain forms and surveys and effect transactions on your behalf.

If you instruct us to, we will use your personal information stored in your student account to help you with the following:

  * Filling out college and university applications for admission and financial aid and scholarship applications
  * Using financial aid calculators to help you determine what certain opportunities may cost
  * Searching for scholarship opportunities
  * Creating and maintaining your Plan of Study, including using coursework planners that assist you in selecting courses and meeting admission requirements
  * Career planning, including assistance with building a resume, cover letters and thank you letters
  * Contacting colleges, universities, and organizations to request information or materials
  * Allowing a school counselor, or other authorized individual, at the school, institution, college or organization which you have designated to view information that you have saved in your CaliforniaColleges.edu portfolio so that they may assist you with your college and career planning efforts.
  * Allowing us to diagnose problems with CaliforniaColleges.edu servers or to adequately administer the CaliforniaColleges.edu website

### With Whom Personal Identifying Information May Be Shared

Any time you request that we perform a task that involves a transfer of data, the data necessary to perform that task will be made available to the person or organization (like a college) that you designate or to a service provider that assists us to complete that task. For example:

  * When you submit an application for admission to a college, the personal data required to complete that application will be provided on your behalf to the admissions office of the institution you specify.
  * When you request that your data be transferred to the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA), data relevant to that application will be provided to the processor specified and authorized by the U.S. Department of Education to process your FAFSA application.
  * When you want a college or other educational institution to send you information about the institution, your contact information will be provided to that institution.
  * When you select your school, college or organization to have access to your student portfolio, or connect your portfolio to counselors at a community based organization of your choosing, authorized individuals at such entities will be able to view information in it.

### Non-Personally Identifiable Data Shared with Others

At times, we may produce reports or combine student user data and provide these reports or combined data sets to various entities including colleges and other educational institutions and agencies. Some examples of summary data that we might share are the number of monthly visitors to the site, the number of admission applications submitted over CaliforniaColleges.edu website, and the CaliforniaColleges.edu functions used by students in specified age or grade ranges.

Whenever we share information for these purposes, we will not reveal any personally identifiable information.

### Security Measures To Prevent Misuse Of Information Entrusted To CaliforniaColleges.edu?

CaliforniaColleges.edu causes the data you input to be encrypted (coded) when en route between your browser and the CaliforniaColleges.edu server and when en route between the CaliforniaColleges.edu server and some other browser or server. This practice helps prevent unauthorized third parties from intercepting and gaining access to your private data during transmission over the Internet. CaliforniaColleges.edu uses 128-bit, Secure Socket Layer encryption supported by current browsers.

Data residing on the CaliforniaColleges.edu server is password-protected. Access to your student account and portfolio is provided only to:

  1. you as the account holder who created the password; and
  2. employees of XAP who need access to administer and maintain the CaliforniaColleges.edu system or to provide requested customer support to users of CaliforniaColleges.edu. Each employee who has access to the data residing on the CaliforniaColleges.edu server has agreed in writing to respect the privacy of all personal data.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small file that a website transfers to a user's computer, which may then be stored on its hard drive. CaliforniaColleges.edu uses cookies to remember you and personalize your web-viewing experience by keeping track of your session when logged on to CaliforniaColleges.edu. Cookies enable you to maintain continuity as you move from page to page on CaliforniaColleges.edu and to avoid the nuisance of being asked to provide the same information repeatedly. Cookies also allow us to make sure that only your browser can exchange information regarding your account with our servers. Cookies cannot be used to steal personal information or to gain access to information that you did not directly provide. The cookies we use are set when you log on to CaliforniaColleges.edu and are erased when you log off CaliforniaColleges.edu or completely close your browser.

Don't want cookies? Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you don't want cookies, you can set your browser to disable or refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being used. You should note, however, that various CaliforniaColleges.edu services might not function properly when cookies are not utilized.

### Links

CaliforniaColleges.edu hosts links to other sites or resources, and you may link to one of those sites or resources for a variety of purposes, such as visiting an official college website. These sites and resources have privacy policies that may differ from that of CaliforniaColleges.edu, and for your protection, we recommend that you read and understand the privacy policy at any website prior to providing personal information on that website.

Neither CCGI nor XAP is responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any websites to which CaliforniaColleges.edu links or for the conduct of persons operating those websites. CCGI, XAP, and the colleges, the associations of colleges and the agencies represented on CaliforniaColleges.edu do not have control over, and do not endorse such external sites and resources. CCGI, XAP and the colleges, the associations of colleges, and the agencies represented on CaliforniaColleges.edu shall not be liable for any content, advertising, products, or other materials on or available from such sites or resources. In addition, CCGI, XAP and the colleges, the associations of colleges, and the agencies represented on CaliforniaColleges.edu shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such content, advertising, products, or materials on or available through any such site or resource.

### Modifying and Deleting Your Information

You may update, otherwise modify, or delete any of the personal information you provide to the CaliforniaColleges.edu website. In cases where data was provided by your school or school district, you may not be able to update, delete or otherwise modify the data, except through procedures of the school or school district.

To **modify** your personal information,

> (i) sign in to CaliforniaColleges.edu,   
>  (ii) access either your portfolio or an application containing the information you want to change, and   
>  (iii) modify that information using standard word-processing techniques.

To **delete** personal information that is not a required field to be completed in your portfolio,

> (i) sign in to CaliforniaColleges.edu,   
>  (ii) access your portfolio, and   
>  (iii) delete the information you want to remove from CaliforniaColleges.edu using standard word-processing techniques, and (iv) save the change.

To delete personal information that is a required field for your portfolio, you will need to contact XAP at 1-800-GOTO-XAP and request that your profile be deleted.

If you delete information, it will no longer be available on CaliforniaColleges.edu so that, for example, if a college to which you previously submitted an application tried to retrieve your application from CaliforniaColleges.edu after you made the deletion, the deleted information would no longer be accessible. Similarly, when accessed over CaliforniaColleges.edu information that has been updated or otherwise modified will appear in its then-most current form, rather than in the form in which it may have been submitted at some earlier time.

### Compliance with Privacy Laws

The CaliforniaColleges.edu Website complies fully with the requirements of the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974, as amended, 20 U.S.C. Sec. 1232g (FERPA), and all federal and state guidelines applicable and adopted in accordance therewith.

Further, in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, 15 U.S.C. Sec. 6501-6506 (“COPPA”) and consistent with the Privacy Policy of the Website, no personal information is collected from persons under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of 13 and you create an account on CaliforniaColleges.edu, you will be prevented from entering personal information related to you or your family on the website.

### Contact

If you have any questions about this Policy or if you believe your personal data may have been shared improperly, please contact us at: [support@californiacolleges.edu](mailto:support@californiacolleges.edu).
